epilepsy.com 2019-06-30

# Terms of Use, Disclaimer for Warranties and Liabilities | Epilepsy Foundation

## Epilepsy Foundation Legal Notices

Copyright ©1996-2019 Epilepsy Foundation of America, Inc. Landover, MD. All rights reserved.

The information available on epilepsy.com is the property of the Epilepsy Foundation and is protected by copyright and other intellectual property laws. The names “Epilepsy Foundation”, “Epilepsy Foundation of America”, the “National Walk for Epilepsy”, and the Epilepsy Foundation’s logos are federally registered trademarks of the Epilepsy Foundation of America. No trademarks of the Epilepsy Foundation, including those that are federally registered and others, shall be used by anyone for any purpose without the express, written consent of the Epilepsy Foundation.

Information contained on this website may be displayed, reformatted, printed or for your personal, noncommercial use only. You may not use any of the information on this website to promote, recommend or endorse any commercial product. You agree not to sell, publish, broadcast or circulate the information on this website for commercial gain, unless you have received specific written permission from the Epilepsy Foundation. Any copy made of information obtained from this website must include the copyright notice

### DISCLAIMER OF WARRANTIES AND LIABILITY

The information contained on this website is for information purposes only, and you assume full responsibility and risk for the appropriate use of medical information contained herein. Do not make changes in your treatment, including medication or lifestyle, as a result of any information you receive on this website, and be sure to consult with your physician or licensed health care provider before changing any medical treatment. The Epilepsy Foundation does not provide individual medical or legal advice on this website and does not directly or indirectly practice medicine or dispense medical services. Consult your own physician or lawyer for specific advice about your personal situation.

The “For Professionals” section of this website is intended to provide information to health care professionals about the current treatment and understanding of the epilepsies. Laypeople who read this information are warned against making any changes in their treatment based upon the information here without consulting their personal physician or licensed health care provider. While the Foundation has made every effort to ensure the accuracy of this information, medical knowledge changes quickly, and changes may have occurred since this information was last reviewed by professionals. Information may also not be complete; the practitioner is therefore urged to continually seek up-to-date information and may contact the Epilepsy Foundation for assistance in doing so. Some treatments recommended in this section of the website, while in line with generally accepted best medical practice, may not be approved by the U.S. Food and Drug Administration for the described uses. Consult the Physicians' Desk Reference and product manufacturer for approved uses and additional information.

While the Epilepsy Foundation takes pride in providing accurate and up-to-date information about epilepsy and its consequences, there may be omissions or inaccuracies in such information and on this website. The Epilepsy Foundation, its officers, directors, employees or agents, does not warrant or guarantee the accuracy or completeness of its information or services, and specifically disclaims any liability therefore.

  **Community Forums, Chats and Social Media Disclaimer:**

The community forums, chat rooms, comments on articles, and social media sharing are provided as a free service of the Epilepsy Foundation.

  * The community forums and chat room are created by the Epilepsy Foundation; however posts within the forums and chat rooms are created by individual users. Article comments are created by individual users. The Epilepsy Foundation does not provide 24/7 monitoring of the community features. Forum or article posts may be reviewed periodically. Inappropriate posts may be removed or managed according to the terms of use. Transcripts of chat rooms may be reviewed periodically.
  * The content posted in any section of the Community (forums, article comments, chat rooms) does not represent the views or opinions of the Epilepsy Foundation.
  * If you object to content posted in the Community, please notify the Foundation via [contactus@efa.org](mailto:contactus@efa.org). Once brought to the attention of the Epilepsy Foundation, we will take all appropriate action to remove or edit postings. Also, some community members may plan in-person meetings. The Foundation does not sponsor nor endorse any of these meetings and your participation in them is at your own risk. The Epilepsy Foundation does not take responsibility or control of these types of meetings and disclaims any liability for any damages or consequences associated with them.

### COMMUNITY GUIDELINES

Welcome to the Epilepsy Foundation community. In order to create the best possible experience for everyone, we ask that you abide by the Epilepsy.com Community Guidelines in all of your activities on the website. The community is exclusively for epilepsy-related issues.

Violations of the Community Guidelines can lead to actions ranging from a warning to suspension or outright termination. We expect all content and activities on the website, whether generated by the Epilepsy Foundation, its partners, or its members, to comply with the Community Guidelines. By content we mean the information, software, communications, images, sounds, and all the material and information that members and others generate on the website.

We do not pre-screen member-generated content generally, but we reserve the right to remove content that does not comport with the Community Guidelines and to ban violators. As with most websites, conversations are open to the public and may be monitored; do not expect privacy.

Users must not generate more than one user name without permission from the webmaster. If more than one person uses the same computer, they may each request individual usernames.

**Respect Others**

  * Do not harass, abuse or threaten another member. If you disagree with someone, respond to the subject, not the person. Do not threaten harm to yourself. These actions may result in your being banned from the website.
  * Do not use hate speech. Hate speech is unacceptable, and the Epilepsy Foundation reserves the right to take appropriate action against any account using the service to post, transmit, promote, distribute or facilitate distribution of content intended to victimize, harass, degrade or intimidate an individual or group on the basis of age, disability, ethnicity, gender, race, religion or sexual orientation.
  * Do not impersonate any person, business or other entity. Doing so in an attempt to deceive, harass, or otherwise mislead another user is forbidden. You may not pretend to be an employee or representative of Epilepsy.com, the Epilepsy Foundation or the Epilepsy Therapy Project.
  * Do not use the website to buy, sell or advertise commercial products.

**Know and Abide by the Law**

It is your responsibility to know and abide by the law. If you fail to do so, the Epilepsy Foundation reserves the right to take any action it deems warranted. You may not publish, post, transmit, promote, or distribute material (including software, photos, sounds and written material) that is illegal or incites illegal activity, or use the website to conduct illegal activities. We terminate accounts and cooperate with law enforcement on such matters.

### NOTICE OF COPYRIGHT INFRINGEMENT

The following agent has been designated to receive notification of claimed infringement of copyright regarding information contained on this website:

Phil Gattone, President & CEO  
Epilepsy Foundation  
8301 Professional Place  
Landover, MD 20785-7223  
(301) 459-3700

### PRIVACY STATEMENT

The Epilepsy Foundation wants to protect the privacy of visitors to our website. The information users voluntarily share with us will be used to improve the quality of our services and to promote public understanding and education about the impact of epilepsy on people's lives. The Foundation has adopted the following privacy policy governing its website. The privacy policy is continuously being revised, and we welcome your thoughts, which you may send to [ContactUs@efa.org](mailto:ContactUs@efa.org). Users who have provided us contact information will be informed upon changes to our privacy policy.

**What personally identifiable information does the Foundation collect from me?**

The Epilepsy Foundation respects the personal privacy of the visitors to our website. We believe keeping your information private and in a secure environment is very important. When you browse the informational portion of our website, you do so anonymously. Personal information is not collected, unless you voluntarily provide us with that information as described below. To participate in our Community, you must provide an e-mail address/user name and password. (Please note that it is not a closed community and posts can be found via search engine outside of the website.) We will not share with third parties your name, street address, telephone number or e-mail address without your consent. We do not sell or rent your personal information. We provide no mechanism for an advertiser to reach you, unless you sign up directly with an advertiser or outside vendor.

In order for the epilepsy.com website to improve its performance and design and to provide you with better services, we track anonymous aggregate usage information through analysis of log files. The type of information collected is basic statistical data, such as channels and sections viewed, time of access and amount of time, search phrases used to reach the Foundation's website, and browser type. This information is not personally identifying you in any way, and we cannot get back to you, the user, through this data. We use this aggregated information in order to learn what are the most popular sections of our website, for general promotional purposes and for making decisions about the future strategy and direction of the website. The aggregated information may also be shared with third parties to promote Epilepsy Foundation services and the website or to add to general knowledge concerning the public's need for epilepsy education and treatment services.

**What happens when I sign up with the Foundation online?**

You voluntarily provide us with personal information when you choose to become a website member, make a donation, join our Speak Up Speak Out grassroots network or Newsroom, join our Community, subscribe to one of our e-newsletters, participate in a research campaign and when you purchase a product from our catalog or online store. The information we collect through these transactions includes such things as your name, address, phone number, email address and, when you make a financial transaction, your credit card number. This allows the Foundation to send you messages and to share information with you that we think you may find useful. We study our users' demographics, interests and behavior based on this information voluntarily provided for a variety of reasons, including to have better information on the needs of people with epilepsy and how to improve our services.

Donor records are kept in the strictest of confidence. At times, we select and offer portions of our mailing list to carefully screened organizations that we believe may interest you. If you do not want to receive this information, or if you would like to have your name removed from future communications, please let us know by sending an email to [ContactUs@efa.org](mailto:ContactUs@efa.org).

**What is a cookie and how does the Foundation use them?**

When you voluntarily join [www.epilepsy.com](http://www.epilepsy.com/), make a donation, or purchase an item from the Foundation, a cookie is placed on your computer hard drive. A cookie is a small amount of data stored as a text file. The data contains a unique identification number assigned by our system that recognizes your browser when you come to our computer, but does not recognize you as an individual. These cookies remain on your system and are automatically retrieved when you return to our website at a later time. We use cookies to remind us of who you are in order to send you information you have requested and deliver to you a more personalized service. The cookie also allows us to automatically log you in to certain sections of our website without having you re-enter user name information for each return visit.

You may choose to set the Internet properties of your computer so that you are alerted each time a cookie is being stored on your computer or you may choose to prohibit the collection of cookies all together. In addition, you may delete cookies that have already been stored on your hard drive. If you do prohibit the collection of cookies, understand that you will need to re-enter your email and other information each time you go to the portion of our website that requires the input of identifying information.

**How do I change my personal information or stop receiving online information from the Foundation?**

If you need to change your personal information, you may do so yourself at any time by simply going to the part of the website where you registered for [www.epilepsy.com](http://www.epilepsy.com/) or purchased items by entering the corrected information. If you decide that you no longer want to receive newsletters, subscriptions to community forums, marketing or other information from the Foundation sent to your email address, you may unsubscribe by updating your profile on [www.epilepsy.com](http://www.epilepsy.com/). If you are a member of the Foundation and would like to update your records, please contact the Foundation by telephone (1-800-332-1000) or letter. (Epilepsy Foundation; ATTN: Epilepsy.com; 8301 Professional Place, Suite 200; Landover, MD 20785-2353.

**How does the Foundation protect my confidential information?**

If you have shared with us your credit card number in order to purchase an item from our online store or to make a donation to the Foundation, your credit card number is stored on a secure server and is protected by firewalls. The Foundation uses computer encrypted technology to protect your information and this information is kept confidential. The Foundation sometimes contracts with outside vendors and business partners to fulfill customer services and hosting services on the website. When we do so, we enter into confidentiality and non-disclosure agreements with all vendors stating that they will hold information received through our website confidential and will not sell or share user information to any third party or use the information for their own personal use. All employees of the Epilepsy Foundation are held accountable for our privacy principles and each employee is personally responsible for maintaining customer confidence in the company.

For more information on the privacy policy related to purchasing from our online store, click here:  
<http://shop.epilepsyfoundation.org/store/help/privacy.aspx>

For more information on the privacy policy related to our eCommunities, click here:  
<http://epilepsyfoundation.ning.com/main/authorization/privacyPolicy?previousUrl=http%3A%2F%2Fepilepsyfoundation.ning.com%2F>

The Foundation may disclose information to law enforcement and other governmental or court authorities in the rare case when we are required to do so or if there is reason to believe that disclosure is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) the Epilepsy Foundation's rights or property, other website users or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities.

**How are children who use the Foundation's website protected?**

The Foundation is concerned about the safety of minors who use the Internet. We want you and your family to feel secure when visiting our website. Children under 13:  Do not send us any information about yourself or your family if you are under age 13 - including information like your name, address or email address - unless you have asked your parents for permission to do so. The Foundation will not knowingly request personal identifying information from children under the age of 18 without parental consent. If we learn that we have personal information from a child under 18, we will delete that information from our database as soon as possible. The Community Forums and Chat Rooms are intended for use by people age 13 or older.

**Linked Internet Websites**

The Foundation hyperlinks to numerous websites that we believe are of interest to people with epilepsy. We do not control the privacy policies of business partners, advertisers, sponsors or other websites to which we may provide hyperlinks, and the privacy policies of any of these third parties may differ from ours. When you hyperlink to the website of one of our business partners, advertisers, sponsors, or other websites, you are subject to their privacy policies and not those of the Foundation. The Epilepsy Foundation is not responsible for such provisions and expressly disclaims any and all liability related to the privacy policy or practices of such other websites.

**Where should I go if I have a question or a complaint about the Foundation's privacy policy and practices?**

The Epilepsy Foundation is committed to efficiency and transparency. We communicate with our supporters, donors, and prospective donors by email, postal mail, phone, and other means, both to request contributions to our cause and to educate the public about epilepsy and seizures, volunteer opportunities, and events in local communities and around the world. These efforts help advance our mission to lead the fight to overcome the challenges of living with epilepsy and to accelerate therapies to stop seizures, find cures, and save lives. As a result, in accordance with the Financial Accounting Standards Board (FASB) guidelines and Internal Revenue Service (IRS) guidance, the Epilepsy Foundation allocates a portion of our fundraising costs to program services. As a nonprofit organization that is exempt from federal taxation, we ensure our donors’ money is spent as efficiently and effectively as possible.

If you have any additional questions about your privacy on the Epilepsy Foundation's website, or if you believe that your privacy may have been violated by the Foundation, please feel free to contact the Foundation at [ContactUs@efa.org](mailto:ContactUs@efa.org).

### MY SEIZURE DIARY

By using the Epilepsy Foundation My SEIZURE Diary feature, you agree to the following terms and conditions:

If you create a personal Diary, you are the only user who can view and edit your information unless you choose to share your information with other users. If you chose to share your information with others including caregivers, family or your clinicians, you can view a list of who has access to your information. Your provision of access to your personal Diary by others may result in third parties misusing your information and is at your own risk. At any time you can take away someone’s ability to access your personal Diary and that person will no longer be able to read your health-related information, but they may have already seen or may retain a copy of the information. The Epilepsy Foundation (owner of Epilepsy.com) may use and disclose the health-related information collected from your personal Diary as described in the Privacy Policy.

You are responsible for taking all reasonable steps to ensure that no unauthorized person shall have access to your Epilepsy Foundation passwords or accounts and for choosing a username and password on Epilepsy.com that would not compromise security on any other website. For technical help with your personal Diary, you may have to provide your user name and password to the website. You should not enter information into the diary or medical organizer that would identify you personally.

You will not receive any payment or other reimbursement for use of the information entered into the Diary. 

The Diary do not provide diagnosis, treatment or other medical advice. You should seek those from your doctors. If you are having a medical emergency, DO NOT use the Diary to communicate with your doctor.

If you have any additional questions about your privacy on the Epilepsy Foundation's My Seizure Diary, please feel free to contact the Foundation at [diary@efa.org](mailto:diary@efa.org?subject=Diary%20Privacy).
